These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2024-10 were created by ZoowlCZ.
ⓘ Very special thanks to Gwaith-i-Phethdain, Magpie of A Magpie's Nest and Friends, and Monoverantus
for their extraordinary work on deciphering the dialogs and lyrics.
ⓘ For correct displaying of these subtitles, use a media player
supporting ASS tags in .srt files.
[Sindarin] Hiro hyn hîdh ab ’wanath.
[English] May they find peace after death.
[Sindarin] Aragorn, nad no ennas!
[English] A thing to be there!
[Sindarin] Man cenich?
[English] What do you see?
[Rohirric] ♫ Bealocwealm hafað fréone frecan forth onsended. ♫
♫ [English]  ♫ An evil death has set forth the noble warrior. ♫
[Rohirric] ♫ giedd sculon singan gléomenn sorgiende... ♫
[English] ♫ A song shall sing sorrowing minstrels... ♫
[Rohirric] ♫ ...on Meduselde þæt he ma no wære... ♫
[English] ♫ ...in Meduseld that he is no more... ♫
[Rohirric] ♫ ...his dryhtne dyrest and mæga deorost. ♫
[English] ♫ ...to his lord dearest and kinsmen most beloved. ♫
[Rohirric] ♫ Bealo... ♫
[English] ♫ An evil death... ♫
[Rohirric]  Simbelmynë.
[English] Evermind.
[Rohirric] Westu hál...
[English] Be-thou well...
[Rohirric] Ferðu, Théodred, Ferðu.
[English] Go-thou, Théodred, go-thou.
[Rohirric] Fæste.
[English] Fast.
[Rohirric] Stille nú.
[English] Calm now.
[Rohirric] Fæste.
[English] Fast.
[Rohirric] Stille.
[English] Calm.
[Rohirric] Lac is drefed, gefrægon.
[English] A battle is stirred up, they heard.
[Rohirric] Hwæt nemnað ðe?
[English] What is your name?
[Rohirric] Ðin nama is cynglic.
[English] Your name is kingly.
[Sindarin] Man le trasta, Brego?
[English] What troubles you, Brego?
[Sindarin] Man cenich?
[English] What did you see?